

ABOUT ME

Synthesizing ideas & solving problems by going on the details always be the motivation in the work areas of software engineering and management. A professional with high adaptability, with extensive experiences throughout the end-to-end of building an application, from requirements analysis to deployment release, from database to user-facing experience.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, COMPUTER **SCIENCE**

University of Indonesia /

SKILLS

COMMUNICATION. PUBLIC RELATION. INTERPERSONAL SKILLS, PUBLIC **SPEAKING**

TEAM MANAGEMENT, PROJECT MANAGEMENT, AGILE SOFTWARE **DEVELOPMENT (SCRUM),** STAKEHOLDERS MANAGEMENT, CHANGE MANAGEMENT, RISK **MANAGEMENT**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE: RUBY, GO, JAVA, KOTLIN, HTML, CSS, JS, PERL

CLOUD: GCP, DISTRIBUTED SYSTEM: DOCKER, KUBERNETES, DATABASE: MYSQL, POSTGRESQL, MONGODB, CASSANDRA, REDIS, MESSAGE QUEUE: RABBITMQ, KAFKA, GOOGLE PUBSUB, SEARCH: ELASTICSEARCH, KIBANA, DEVELOPMENT: GITHUB, GITLAB, OLAP: BIGQUERY, CI/CD: GITLAB

LANGUAGES

AGUSTINUS ARDHITO VEDOPUTRO

SENIOR DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING MANAGER

- Komplek Samudera Indonesia No. 3, Pasar Minggu, Jakarta Selatan, DKI Jakarta 12520, Jakarta, 12520, Indonesia

+62-817-6567-424

≥ agusdhito@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

GOVTECHEDU INDONESIA

Jakarta Jul 2024 - Dec 2024

Senior Development Engineering Manager

- Managing growing the skills of 10+ team members with various backgrounds & skills (BE, FE, Software Architect, QA)
- Migrating the architecture of 5+ mio users from open-source project to in-house solution, from Python to Golang & NextJS
- Managing data-visualization platform with 10.000+ RPS with 10+ data sources & pipelines
- Efffectively communicating &collaborating to 40+ other team members with various backgrounds like Product, Design, Data, Marketing, Customer Ops, Infrastructure, Regulators, etc

GOVTECHEDU INDONESIA

Jakarta Apr 2022 - Jun 2024

Development Engineering Manager

- Giving impacts to 500.000+ schools and 5+ mio teachers across the horizon of Indonesia
- Managing growing the skills of 10+ team members with various backgrounds & skills (BE, FE, Software Architect, QA)
- Managing data-visualization platform with 10.000+ RPS with 10+ data sources & pipelines
- Efffectively communicating & collaborating to 40+ other team members with various backgrounds like Product, Design, Data, Marketing, Customer Ops, Infrastructure, Regulators, etc

PT. **BUKALAPAK.COM**

Jakarta Jan 2021 - Mar 2022

Engineering Manager

- Managing & growing team of 7+ members with various backgrounds like BE, FE, Android, iOS
- Leading & managing Core Account management system serving 50000+ RPS with 40+ mio users throughout company & its subsidiaries
- Leading technical design for features such as OAuth, Login, Register, OTP with 20+ stateless & statefull dependencies
- Managing & communicating with 10+ stakeholders and 20+ teams to ensure 3+ project timeline & expecations at one time
- Reviewing architecture design proposed by other teams 2 times per week

PT **BUKALAPAK.COM**

Jakarta Jun 2017 - Dec 2020

Software Engineer - Backend

- Designing scalable, maintainable & reliable software along with its state & stateless dependencies with 50.000+ RPS and 30+ mio users
- Creating & managing & migrating 50+ REST API
- Designing, developing & maintaining 5+ micro-services' infrastructure & architecture system

RAHASA

FNGLISH

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth 09 Aug 1995

Nationality Indonesia

- Leading & coaching 3+ members of the team for work assignments, and technical discussions & decisions
- Handling production issues/incidents & fraud attacks in timely manner, with up to IDR 1+ bio transactions value

BADAN LITBANG PERTANIAN (BALITBANGTAN) RI

Jakarta Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Software Engineer Intern - Apps

• Developing chat mobile apps using Android Studio